[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
[wind howls]
Hey, it's getting kind of drafty in here.
I can barely hear myself think.
[wind howls]
Oh, yeah, that's a breeze all right.
I wonder how far I can make my spit go
[wind howls]
if I was to hock a loogie into the...
no, better not.
[wind howls]
Too bad the bodies landed on the
other side of the door,
[wind howls]
then I could just toss them in and
watch them explode.
[wind howls]
COME ON! THIS IS STUPID!
Huh? What about the keypad?
[wind howls]
Yeah!
WAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA--
[wind howls]
OOF!
[ragged coughing]
[wind howls]
[wheeze]
[raspy voice] How is this happening...?
[wind howls]
[raspy voice] Just let me out of here...
[raspy voice] Jesus Christ...
[wind howls]
[raspy voice] This must be a windspeed
[raspy voice] of 150 miles an hour...
[wind howls]
[raspy voice] Stop persecuting me...
[raspy voice] all of you...
[wind howls]
[raspy voice] Stop... stop...
[raspy voice] I guess now I know
why that door wouldn't open.
[raspy voice] That must be why
those boards were up there, too.
[raspy voice] Shhh.
[raspy voice] This must've
happened before.
[raspy voice] I bet they used to
have it lined with spikes.
[raspy voice] Then, one day they came in
and found the janitor impaled on the ceiling.
[raspy voice] I mean, my God, I'm not
even wearing air-resistant clothing.
[raspy voice] I thought you had to be
wearing MC Hammer pants and a poncho
[raspy voice] for that to work.
[raspy voice] You don't deal
with this in theoretical physics.
[raspy voice] It's just numbers,
but rocket scientists don't
have that excuse.
They have to test the rockets,
no matter how many people get killed.
But I respect that.
You know?
Huh?!
DO YOU PEOPLE HEAR ANYTHING I'M SAYING?!
I DON'T THINK YOU DO!
"Oxy"? Is this oxycodone?!
Oh, no, it's probably just oxygen.
I don't think you can get high
off oxygen; it just makes you more alert.
I don't really know what I'm
doing, but, y'know,
pushing buttons and having it do
something is sort of its own reward.
Not that I don't have better
things to be doing with my time.
I need to start looking for a new job
and get cracking on that lawsuit.
I've got shit to do!
God dammit! This is that door
that wouldn't open!
I'VE GONE IN CIRCLES AGAIN!
[growls]
Actually, I don't feel like
looking for a new job.
I want to go on vacation like
Hawaii or some place in the Caribbean.
Actually, what I really want is a rebreather
so then I can tame a giant sea turtle
and learn how to ride it.
Once I can ride a sea turtle,
that opens up some options.
Then I can come up on
cruise ships undetected
and shoot tranquilizer darts
at the passengers.
That'd be fun.
Actually, if I had some
ninja claws, I could
scale... the side... of the boat...
and then come aboard
at night and rob people.
I mean, y'know a cruise ship
would be loaded with loot.
And I'd have the perfect
getaway vehicle: my sea turtle.
Hell, I could get the
vacation to pay for itself.
[tentacles moan]
I think I'd name the sea turtle "Flippy".
That's a good gender-neutral name.
[tentacles moan]
Or maybe I'd call it "Whiskers" as a joke,
because that's what you'd name a cat.
[metal banging]
The cruise ship guests would think
that's pretty funny until I
[metal banging]
pulled a gun on them.
[tentacles moan]
[metal banging]
Wow, you might be a reptile
but you're really dangerous.
[metal banging]
You're not like a turtle at all.
[tentacles moan]
I don't like that.
[explosion, tentacles moan]
[metal banging]
God, how can this thing
just shrug off a grenade?
[metal banging]
It should kill anything.
God, STOP BANGING! JESUS!
[metal banging]
You know, some cultures sacrifice
people to volcanoes or whatever.
[metal banging]
I'd sacrifice people to this thing
if it would keep it quiet.
[tentacles moan]
Man, now it's blocking the way
I want to go.
[metal banging]
I have no sympathy
for this thing whatsoever.
[tentacles moan]
[metal banging]
God!
Yeah, that's right!
[metal banging]
You show that metal floor who's boss!
Don't take "no" for an answer!
[metal banging]
Yeah, they'll be handing out
defense contracts like candy
[tentacles moan]
once they see a monster that's
immune to grenades.
Money money money.
Man, between suing Black Mesa
and being in a key field for a new job,
I might be able to fund building
a robot army like I always wanted to.
Dammit, I can't jump this!
Jackie Chan couldn't jump this!
Well, maybe he could if he kicked off
from wall to wall, but I'm not that good.
Ah, see, if I had a grappling hook,
I could throw it up there and swing across.
Maybe.
Maybe it's just as well I don't
have a grappling hook.
Oh, what am I saying?
Of course I want a grappling hook,
or a harpoon or something.
Of course, the real problem here is that
[metal banging]
Earth's gravity is just too damned high.
See, case in point.
If I was on Mars, I wouldn't even
have to think about this gap,
but as it stands, I'm like a monkey
trying to decide whether he can
reach the next branch or not.
It's a wonder we've even made it this far.
We should've all fallen from
trees and be extinct right now.
Okay, focus. Don't die.
Don't die.
Hup!
[metal banging]
Oh God.
Don't want to do that again.
[metal banging]
This would be more fun if
I was an adrenaline-junkie.
[tentacles roar]
[BANG]
[metal banging]
Oh, now I know I'm going the right way.
[tentacles moan]
Right.
Jesus Christ...
[tentacles moan]
[growls]
[metal banging]
If you think I won't shoot you in the back
you're mistaken.
[metal banging]
Okay, everybody's dead.
Just the way I like it.
[metal banging]
God, my knees are shaking from
going across those gaps.
[metal banging]
You'd think I'd be getting used to
doing leaps and edging my way
[metal banging]
along ledges
but there's always that chill knowing
that if I make one small mistake,
I'll be dead within seconds.
I'm not used to performance
reviews like that.
Okay, so I should NOT shoot the
gas canisters with a shotgun.
I think I'm getting it.
I'm starting to see how someone
could go crazy down here.
I'm seeing monsters as big as a building,
ones that teleport out of the air,
soldiers trying to kill me,
a giant building with no exits,
a crazy-o-meter...
But see, now it's kind of
peaceful and quiet,
and it makes me wonder if I'm
just imagining everything.
But no matter how sane or
rational I think I am,
I'M STILL STUCK IN THIS BUILDING!
[houndeyes charging up]
Oh. Good.
Perfect.
[sonic boom]
[houndeye chirruping]
Yeah, see, this is what I'm talking about.
Everything's fine then chirping maggots
with legs start popping around the corner.
That's crazy. I'm not crazy
and I know that's crazy.
[bullsquid moans]
Yeah, that's right, moan!  MOAN!
That noise is exactly what I'll be thinking
about when I try to go to sleep tonight.
And I'll be dreaming about you sucking
out my eyes with your tentacle face,
while I'm nestled up against a
stack of rotted corpses,
then my intestines will burst
with insects crawling out of them,
then the screaming--jeez,
that's a long drop.
Uh huh.
That's it. I'm going to order a
grappling hook when I'm get out of here.
This is never going to happen again.